A Guide to the Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA802 FA802
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
  - Printed materials (Box 33)
    - St. John's College. 1943-44 catalogue, with extract from p. 65, marked and copied by Cohn, 1943-1944 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous [Clipping from Playbill for "Finian's Rainbow, " April 1947, 46th St. Theatre] (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Manuscripts, [1 Oct 1985: ck.] (Box 34)
    - Auriculo nodal junction, circa 1909 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - A case of heart block (Dora Stein, Auricular flutter), circa 1911 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Auricular tachycardia, circa 1911-1912 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Adrenals, circa 1908 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Sino-auricular node, circa 1911-1912; 2 folders (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
    - Production of reversed cardiac mechanism in the dog, circa 1912 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Post-morten exam of horses hearts, circa 1912-1913 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Cohn and Fraser. Paroxysmal tachycardia, circa 1913 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Effect of morphin, circa 1913 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Cohn and Heard. Auricular fibrillation with post-mortem exam, circa 1913 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Cohn and Fraser. Auricular contraction, circa 1913-1914 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Cohn and W.H. Lewis. Digitalis and pneumonia, circa 1933-1935; 5 folders (Box 34, Folder 13-17)
    - W.H. Lewis. American Journal of Physiology, circa 1938; 5 folders (Box 34, Folder 18-22)
  - Miscellaneous materials, Folders 1-17 are legal size; Folders 18-50 are letter size; [16 July 1986: ck] (Box 35)
    Including oversize material removed from previous boxes; biographical, correspondence, personal.
    - Clinical notes (EKG) (Box 35)
      - 1919 May 16-September 30 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - 1919 October 1-December 30 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - 1921 July 5-December 31 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - untitled, Oversize material, removed from files packed in letter-size folders (Box 35)
      - U(5)10 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - U(5)23 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - U(14)13 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - U(14)16 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - U(14)21 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - U(14)23 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - U(14)25 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - U(14)26 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - U(14)28 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - U(17)17 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - U(18)12 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - U(18)13 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - U(18)14 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - U(18)34 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - American Association for Adult Education (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - American.... [Memberships] (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Association... [Memberships] (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - China Medical Board (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Butterick, E.A., 1925 (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Burton, E.D., 1924 (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - Clippings (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Columbia University, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Columbia University. D. Sc, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Medico-Historical Press [Biographical data] (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - New York State Education Department /Medical Society of the State of NY (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - New York... [Memberships] (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - We Europeans by Julian S. Huxley and A.C. Haddon (Harper and Bros, 1936). Correspondence re, 1935-36, primarily with Charles Singer, 1935-1936 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - We Europeans. Book reviews (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Wells College, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - Who's Who... (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - World Biographical Encyclopedia (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - R.H. Macy and Co re book orders, 1928-1935 (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - Quotations and notes (Box 35, Folder 39)
    - Extract of speech given by Mr. Laennec on the opening of his course on medicine at the Collège Royal de France, Typescript copy (Box 35, Folder 40)
    - Preservation of book bindings [1927 article], Typescript copy (Box 35, Folder 41)
    - [Landsteiner, Karl] Untitled typescript of remarks, apparently given on 40th anniversary of publication (?) of Koch's tuberculin reaction, with 1939 notes re loan of ms. to Dr. Florence Sabin (Box 35, Folder 42)
    - Post Office, circa 1946-1950 (Box 35, Folder 43)
    - Photostat".Instrumental methods in cardiology". British Medical Journal, 1932 January 30 (Box 35, Folder 44)
    - Photostat. "American Notes." The Economist 16 Jul 1949 (Box 35, Folder 45)
      [Includes column re Alger Hiss].
    - Photostat."Voltaire Never Said It! " Modern Language Notes, 1943 November (Box 35, Folder 46)
    - Service Station (Cadillac) (Box 35, Folder 47)
    - Gardens, general (Box 35, Folder 48)
    - Gardens, Wayside (Box 35, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and mss to be interfiled (Box 35, Folder 50)
  - EKG Records, 1920s-1930s (Box 36-41)
  - Miscellaneous - Reprints, Addresses, Articles (Box 42)
    Includes some material on Home for Aged (Jewish), (also Speeches).
  - Correspondence—Miscellaneous, circa 1930s (Box 43)
  - Memorabilia (Box 44)
    - Membership cards, EKGs & polygraphic tracings (in box), microfilm—"The Burden of Diseases in the United States" by AEC & Claire Lingg, postcards, index cards, notebook—"Studies in Heart-Lung Preparations, 1927", stamps, pocket calendar, photos
  - Miscellaneous Files (Box 45)
    - printed booklets—AEC author/coauthor
    - Cohn Centennial Exhibition, 1979
    - Library Dedication, 1959
    - "Janeway, T.C. Medical Record"
    - reprints by others, also articles, 1920-1929
    - miscellaneous correspondence
  - OVERSIZE MATERIAL, (oversize), [ck: 7/86] (Box 1)
    - I: Items and folders, legal-size folders from 450 C661-U Paige boxes 5, 14, 17, 18 in 450 C661-U Paige box 35
    - II: Odds and Ends
      Sent to RAC 7/21/1987 by Harold Oakhill & Tom Rosenbaum.
      - 8 rolls of charts
      - 2 EKG ledgers
      - 1 instrument extension cord
    - New York Times, photostat from 23 November 1906, obituary of Edward A. Price, father-in-law of A.E. Cohn. Gift of Paul F. Cranefield, 3 August 1983, 1906 1983; (oversize - Map case)
    - untitled, (oversize - Flat box)
      - New York World's Fair World, Volume 1, Number 1, 1939 (Folder 1)
        Separated Materials
        Removed from: (15) 16
      - New York World's Fair World, Volume 1, Number 3, 1939 (Folder 1)
      - Nurse's Reports September 30-December 4 [1899? ] For Alfred E. Cohn (Folder 2)
        Removed from: (26) 6
      - Satirical drawings and essay, on medical forms from The Mount Sinai Hospital (ca 1907?), unidentified (Folder 3)
        Removed from: (26) 7